<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[失控的前额叶]]></title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-06T15:29:52.612Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ataraxia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Zootopia]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2016/03/06/Diary-03-06-16/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2016/03/06/Diary-03-06-16/</id>
    <published>2016-03-06T14:24:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-03-06T15:29:52.612Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>周五的时候去看了Zootopia，迪士尼新出的电影，主线是兔子警官朱迪为了实现自己的警察梦而不懈奋斗的故事。可以说是符合美国梦的主旋律故事。片子的确很精彩，如果我要评分的话大概会给8分左右。</p>
<p>但是看完电影回来之后稍稍让我有点惊讶，因为大家对它的评价实在太高了，在豆瓣上今天看居然有9.4的评分。这就让我不是很理解了。所以就在想这是为什么？</p>
<p>因为自己也不是很清楚，就随着剧情一边写一边剖析自己的评分的由来吧。</p>
<p>故事开始在朱迪兔兔的小时候，小朱迪还在家里所在的小镇上学。电影的设定是这样的，所有不同种类的动物都生活在一起，食草动物与食肉动物共存。在电影的开始，小朱迪就立志当去zootopia（动物世界最大的城市）当一名警官，但是这个梦想是特别地不切实际，因为在警局都是都是身材高大威猛的动物，而兔子实在显得太不起眼了，一只手无缚鸡之力的兔子能做什么呢？他们的父母也是用各种方式婉言劝阻朱迪。 我们的这位小兔朱迪呢，从小就不服管教…额…是正义心爆棚，每每帮助自己身边同样小伙伴免受高大的<strong>食肉动物</strong>的欺负，然而自己也没少受罪。</p>
<p>15年后，我们的小兔朱迪成功进入了警察学院，受训成为一名警官，然而前期却没有先天优势，被我们其他高大威猛身强力壮的动物兄弟压得好惨，每次批评都第一，“朱迪，你死了。”在电影中出现无数次。然而我们的小兔不甘心啊，然后就力量不行咱可以智取啊，然后就一个劲训练啊，想啊，最后就莫名其妙地变第一毕业了…. <em>这点可能就是我不是特赞同电影设定的一点，不过如果这是我在两年前看的话，一定会感动得不要不要的直接就给电影满分了。其实这个就涉及到美国梦是否可以真的实现的问题了，我们每个人通过不懈努力是否真的可以得到所想要的东西，所以这一点我直接就减分了（论梦想是如何破碎的，破碎后又如何重建人生）</em></p>
<p>咳咳，回到主线。我们的警官朱迪被授予了最佳毕业生的荣誉勋章，并成为警局第一位兔子警官，也顺利地被派往zootopia当警察。(⊙v⊙)嗯，然后就坐上了一辆精心设计过的火车，因为这种火车可以让适配不同个头体型大小的动物，车子简直萌坏了。然后我们的兔兔朱迪警官就随着BGM来到了zootopia（一直觉得这个可以翻译成理想国什么的意思）</p>
<p>-，-忽然发现这居然是个坑，明天再更好了。</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>周五的时候去看了Zootopia，迪士尼新出的电影，主线是兔子警官朱迪为了实现自己的警察梦而不懈奋斗的故事。可以说是符合美国梦的主旋律故事。片子的确很精彩，如果我要评分的话大概会给8分左右。</p>
<p>但是看完电影回来之后稍稍让我有点惊讶，因为大家对它的评价实在太高了，]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Movies" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Movies/"/>
    
      <category term="Amusement" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Amusement/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Diary 03/03/16]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2016/03/03/Diary-03-03-16/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2016/03/03/Diary-03-03-16/</id>
    <published>2016-03-03T14:46:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-03-03T16:13:08.306Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>到学校将近有两个星期了，觉得该写点什么了，因为本博客的宗旨就是记录作为我本身的每一个微小的变化。</p>
<p>因为这个学期来了到现在每周只有2-3节课，基本等于一直在放假。所以作息也是跟在家差不多了=￣ω￣=。晚上依旧很晚地睡，一醒来也就是中午了，下午晚上去自习一会儿，回来再胡乱看看就睡觉了。不想动，不想起。（自从看了去年传说中豆瓣评分最高的三部动漫我也是干脆就认了自己的这种设定了，当然银他妈还没看多少）</p>
<p>所以呢，又和以前一样，开始想怎么样才能打起精神运动，可不可以不要睡那么晚。(⊙v⊙)嗯，每次我一说完都会有几天的奇效，所以我就多唠叨几句。开始想怎么样才能打起精神运动，可不可以不要睡那么晚；开始想怎么样才能打起精神运动，可不可以不要睡那么晚；开始想怎么样才能打起精神运动，可不可以不要睡那么晚。</p>
<p>这个学期一来买了好多手办，别问我为什么要买，我才不会说看到的都辣么便宜还都是正版的，而且只剩一两个，不买让我怎么安心啊啊啊啊。<br>所以说，为什么这个学期一来忽然想起买手办了，因为我对EVA爱得深沉啊。现在身上穿的还是EVA的周边的说。</p>
<p>而且这是我的一个实验的说。因为我一直都对与钱和实用物品挂钩的事情都不太感兴趣，也就是说基本无法激发我的小宇宙。例如吧，虽然报一次托福要1600块，但是这钱是花了，我也知道挺多，按理说我应该好好学吧，但是呢？ 嗯…. 说做完什么什么然后去买件衣服吧，前提是你得做完是吧，但是呢，这衣服你得用啊，你要穿啊，所以你就不知不觉买了衣服，而该做的事情还没做完。（其实我是一直挺不屑这种交换方式的，但这确是人的天性之一，所以其实我更多的是看到什么感兴趣做什么，虽然更多的时候物质回报几乎为零，但当你真正看到了什么不得了的东西的时候，还真的需要很多物质上的回报吗？）</p>
<p>(⊙v⊙)嗯，切回正题。但是，这里面其实有一点我一直都没有注意到，就是当你真正想要买些什么不得了的东西，而这件物品又并不是必需品时，不是买衣服不是吃饭甚至也不是报课程时，就很难有理由来买这些东西了，比如我要买的手办。（都是因为自己不赚钱坐吃父母的锅了-，- ）所以就要有等价交换品了(ノへ￣、)，比如要好好学习啦什么的。妈妈说你总算对钱感兴趣了吧23333.</p>
<p>看中了一个Ayanami Rei哥特萝莉限定版的手办，大概要400块的样子，所以就跟我妈立了魔鬼契约。 没错，就是这么把自己卖了。 然而这么随意地立FLAG真的没问题吗？</p>
<p>然后说说EVA，在刚开始看到人类补完计划的时候其实我是嘲笑的，这什么东西嘛，庵野秀明你丫脑袋是进水了吧，不会真的就天真到相信补完就能变好吧？变好又有什么用呢？抚慰你幼小的心灵？<br>然而现在却有些动摇了…说不上为什么，可能是好久不看，肆意篡改了对动画了记忆了吧？待我过一阵再刷一遍。<br>那我为什么会喜欢EVA呢？ 虽然估计特别多的EVA都讨厌香和绫波最后的结局，我却总是爱得不行。至于为什么以后再说了。</p>
<p>去年豆瓣评分最高的三部动画 Rick and Morty, 银魂，马男Bojack。感觉三部动漫都有一个共同的特点，在看似颓废的外表下都有极正的三观。三部动漫里的人物都不是完美的，都是flawed，这种人你平时看到绝对是烂人一个的。但是你就是喜欢里面的每一个角色，因为他们就像是你身边的最好朋友，你知道他们的喜好和优缺点，你可以永无止境地黑对方。在里面你可以看到住在豪宅里的过气的老马原来生活也是一团糟，从来都交不起房租总是被登势婆婆往出赶的银时也在一直坚守着自己的武士道，把Morty作为频率屏蔽器的Rick也能在生死攸关的时候奋不顾身地去救Morty。想说的太多太多，到要写的时候却总是不知道要写什么了…果然还是表达能力太差。</p>
<p>今天的文风怪怪的…</p>
<p>咳咳，今天就不贴图了，如果我的魔鬼契约能兑现的话，我就会来晒图啦~</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>到学校将近有两个星期了，觉得该写点什么了，因为本博客的宗旨就是记录作为我本身的每一个微小的变化。</p>
<p>因为这个学期来了到现在每周只有2-3节课，基本等于一直在放假。所以作息也是跟在家差不多了=￣ω￣=。晚上依旧很晚地睡，一醒来也就是中午了，下午晚上去自习一会儿，回]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="MyDiary" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/MyDiary/"/>
    
      <category term="Inner_Man" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Inner-Man/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Diary/01/31/16]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2016/01/31/Diary-01-31-16/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2016/01/31/Diary-01-31-16/</id>
    <published>2016-01-31T15:21:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-31T16:30:51.611Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>回来也有两个星期了，昨天刷完了Neuroecnomics的课程，总分97.3%。因为简单所以也是预料之中。<br>然而回来到现在却也感觉没学到什么东西，Medical Neuroscience的Quiz也一个都没刷，今天一看视频也是困意频频来袭，想写点什么又觉得没什么可说的，但总是要写些什么的吧。</p>
<p>最近感觉三观有有了一点点的改变，按照普世的观点应该是好的吧，虽然目前为止还没有在行动上有所体现。但我现在越来越期望一个有着良好学习状态的自己了，而我相信这一天也快来到了。</p>
<p>说说自己的观念哪里变了：</p>
<p>1、对于某理论是用于解释问题还是加以运用。以前是倾向于通过某理论解释问题，然而却很少想根据这个理论我能做出什么改变。从今往后我想我都要加入这个几乎没有被考虑到的因素了。</p>
<p>2、对Follow your heart这句话的理解。前一阵其实已经有点完全任由潜意识来主宰自己了，有点失去了作为理性个体本身所拥有的控制能力。遵从subconscious可以解决一些问题这个我不反对，问题是它本身所固有的属性很多都是我们平时所说的堕落方面的，并不能带来问题的最优解（其实作为人本身也许根本就没有问题的最优解，只有在所拥有的资源下寻找最好的方案）。而我所做的其实是平衡好理性与非理性之间的冲突，提升自我的效率。其实应该以前也是这样做的，但不知道为什么最近却忘记了这方面的探索。也许是对自我很少能真正决定自己的决策行为所感到的悲观以至于放弃自己了吧。  其实，我能做的还有很多，对吧？</p>
<p>所以感觉最近要改改半夜两三点睡的习惯了，回来半个月了，黑眼圈一直都没有消掉。再这样感觉真的要挂掉了…</p>
<p>然后，今天晚歇醒来的一瞬间又重新体验了回对死亡、对虚无的恐惧。中学时候的老毛病了，上大学很少有了。不过也有点好处，能惊醒自己，以防自己就这么一步一步堕落下去。而且吧，今天还想了下出现这种情况的生理学机制，目前认为是醒来的短时间内大脑不同区域的激活成都不同所导致，具体是哪还无从得知。不过这次给了我一点学药学神经学的动力，毕竟每周15+小时的课不是说着玩的，这次要是真能好好跟着学完了收获一定很大的。</p>
<p>最近看知乎这个问题——&gt;<a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/37374497" target="_blank" rel="external">人类有什么细思极恐的细节？</a>的时候发现好多问题之前自己都想过，里面对好多问题的见解都跟以前不一样的。这大概就是我上大学以来真正进步的地方吧，不再跟随问题提出者的思维方式。希望这不要成为我以后理解问题的阻碍。</p>
<p>最后，贴 证 书~(≧▽≦)/~<br><img src="http://i1036.photobucket.com/albums/a443/NightingaleEta/NE_zpsy5wgecoo.png" alt=""></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>回来也有两个星期了，昨天刷完了Neuroecnomics的课程，总分97.3%。因为简单所以也是预料之中。<br>然而回来到现在却也感觉没学到什么东西，Medical Neuroscience的Quiz也一个都没刷，今天一看视频也是困意频频来袭，想写点什么又觉得没什么可说的]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="MyDiary" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/MyDiary/"/>
    
      <category term="Inner_Man" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Inner-Man/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[我又回来啦~]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2016/01/18/2016-01-18/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2016/01/18/2016-01-18/</id>
    <published>2016-01-18T13:19:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-19T02:39:15.088Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>之前因为英文写起来略麻烦，笔记本换了硬盘导致不能上传，旧硬盘数据不能及时导出，又碰上一大波考试来临就一直没有在自己搭好的博客上更新，从今天开始准备将内容大部分写为中文，直到我的英文水平达到中文表达能力的80%以上为止。</p>
<p>Anyway,在寒假开始的这个时候我的小博客又要开始更新啦~(≧▽≦)/~</p>
<p><em>图片测试：</em><br><img src="http://i245.photobucket.com/albums/gg62/witchyhoy3/0a1bcvvvv/image2-8.png" alt=""></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>之前因为英文写起来略麻烦，笔记本换了硬盘导致不能上传，旧硬盘数据不能及时导出，又碰上一大波考试来临就一直没有在自己搭好的博客上更新，从今天开始准备将内容大部分写为中文，直到我的英文水平达到中文表达能力的80%以上为止。</p>
<p>Anyway,在寒假开始的这个时候我的小]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="uncategorized" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/uncategorized/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Diary 10/27/15]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2015/10/27/Diary-10-27-15/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2015/10/27/Diary-10-27-15/</id>
    <published>2015-10-27T15:17:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-31T16:31:24.066Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rencently I found that I have many articles not classified in EverNote,more than 100 articles.<br>I wanna establish my own knowledge system,because Google always knows more than you. Information become knowledge only when you integrate it! Integrate information  including the curriculum itself, between the curriculums, as well as interdisciplinary knowledge integration, these are the most important, and reflect personal values.But I’m  far from that. I have study computer science for two years now, and I think I already have some ideas about the subject. It’s thime for me to try to intergrate the knowledge I have learned.</p>
<p>I just finished the animation Bojeck horseman,use a word to discribe it: Absurd and unreasonable everywhere ,but always touching your heart.<br><strong>I will write a review if I have time.</strong></p>
<p>Finally I finished my compiler principle experiment, but I still have other experiments on Wednesday and Thursday. ╮(╯▽╰)╭</p>
<p>I have not finished The little Prince at present, so, Sun Fei, I have to update it later.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Rencently I found that I have many articles not classified in EverNote,more than 100 articles.<br>I wanna establish my own knowledge syst]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="MyDiary" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/MyDiary/"/>
    
      <category term="Inner_Man" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Inner-Man/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Diary 10/23/15]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2015/10/23/Diary-10-23-15/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2015/10/23/Diary-10-23-15/</id>
    <published>2015-10-23T15:38:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-23T17:27:56.249Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I read a book about “face”  –《看脸》. I’d like to make a summary of the book later.<br>And I read a article about consciousness&amp;vision  this morning – <em>What are we talking about when we say “consciousness”</em><br>Click–&gt;<a href="http://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/visualthinking/20287372" target="_blank" rel="external">我们说『意识』的时候，我们在说些什么?</a><br>This article mainly said that it’s difficult for us to measure consciousness and why difficult?<br>I made a parallelism sentence after reading this article:<br>你以为你说出来的这句话，其实也许并不是他们听到的那句话。（基于对词汇认知的偏差）<br>你以为你披在外面的这张脸，其实也不是别人看到的那张脸。（基于人脸的不对称和个人看镜子与他人看你脸的方向是左右相反的）<br>你以为你看到的这世间万物，其实也并不是别人看到的那世界。（基于人的认知只是客观世界的一小部分）</p>
<p>I saw the movie 《业火的向日葵》today after class, which is another theatrical version about detective Conan.<br>Conan used to be my favorite animation when I was a junior school student,but I don’t fanatical in it anymore. Maybe it just because I can’t get anything touched me except some basic detective knowledge from this animation. It can’t make me think deep and inspired me. But when I saw the moive today,I can still remember every character in all details, waht he like or what she don’t like.<br><em>What you once cherish never dies in the river of time, though these things no longer exist in your life, probably.</em></p>
<p>I still have too many things todo recently, but sometime I just not sure where to start. (I think maybe that’s why I can’t do things well). Another problem is I can’t focus on one thing for a long time(30min or more), and I’am easily to think about the things that not relevant to the subject when I studying. But according to my perspection, some guys can!! We’re totally different kinds of people.o(╯□╰)o</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I read a book about “face”  –《看脸》. I’d like to make a summary of the book later.<br>And I read a article about consciousness&a]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Animation" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Animation/"/>
    
      <category term="Cognitive" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Cognitive/"/>
    
      <category term="Reflection" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Reflection/"/>
    
      <category term="Inner_Man" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Inner-Man/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Diary 10/21/15]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2015/10/21/Diary-10-21-15/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2015/10/21/Diary-10-21-15/</id>
    <published>2015-10-21T13:50:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-31T16:31:04.742Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Share a blog about neuro&amp;brain.<br>Click–&gt;<a href="http://neuroscientist.weebly.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Neuroscience for beginners V2.0</a><br>This blog serves as the notes repository for MOOC Neuroscience ventures which include notes about<br>the course SYNAPSES, NEURONS AND BRAIN. I just finished the course this month, and these notes helped me a lot. </p>
<hr>
<p>I have lots of programming experiment to do in the following few weeks. I think I will spend much more time in study than before because of my poor programming skills. Most of time I just don’t know where to start. So I decide to read some books about how to design programs and review the basic knowledge about C/C++ language.</p>
<p>Here are some books&amp;articles I find today:</p>
<p>How to design programs –MIT Press<br><em>The book introduces the concept of a design recipe, a six-step process for creating programs from the problem statement. While the book was originally used in conjunction with the TeachScheme! project (now ProgramByDesign), it has been adopted at a number of colleges and universities for the teaching of program design principles. –via Wikipedia </em><br>But I won’t read this book recently, because this is discussing about how to design programs using LISP language which different from C/C++/JAVA that I learned.</p>
<p>And another book(or notes?) is 《设计模式精解–GoF 23种设计模式解析 附C++实现源码》<br>This book is more useful to me now.</p>
<p>And I think I should pay more attention to oprate system&amp;database princple. I just haven’t have chance to open these textbooks after class!</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Share a blog about neuro&amp;brain.<br>Click–&gt;<a href="http://neuroscientist.weebly.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Neuroscience ]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="MyDiary" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/MyDiary/"/>
    
      <category term="Inner_Man" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Inner-Man/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hebbian Learning]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2015/10/20/neuro/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2015/10/20/neuro/</id>
    <published>2015-10-20T15:19:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-18T17:10:52.416Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Introduce to a interesting website:<br><a href="http://ncase.me/neurons/?url_type=39&amp;object_type=webpage&amp;pos=1" target="_blank" rel="external">Neurotic Neurons</a><br>This website give us a simple and clear example of Hebbian Learning (a classical theory in nueroscience that propose by Donald Hebb in 1949), using a well designed interactive animation.</p>
<p><em>The most important concept I wanted to introduce here was exposure therapy, which is part of Cognitive Behavioral Therapy. CBT is basically being mindful of your crappy neural connections, and gaining skills to retrain those connections.  –by author</em></p>
<p>Part of the subtitles:</p>
<pre><code><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">//
//</span> MY FEARS <span class="pi">//
//</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span>

<span class="string">"fear0"</span>: <span class="string">"THIS is what happens."</span>,
<span class="string">"fear1"</span>: <span class="string">"Innocent thoughts connect to anxious thoughts."</span>,
<span class="string">"fear2"</span>: <span class="string">"Personally, I used to be so afraid of being seen as a failure,"</span>,
<span class="string">"fear3"</span>: <span class="string">"of being close to people,"</span>,
<span class="string">"fear4"</span>: <span class="string">"and of..."</span>,
<span class="string">"fear5"</span>: <span class="string">"holes."</span>,
<span class="string">"fear6"</span>: <span class="string">"Coz... I don't know why, but tightly clustered holes"</span>,
<span class="string">"fear7"</span>: <span class="string">"just kinda creep me out, y'know? I dunno."</span>,

<span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">//
//</span> HEBBIAN LEARNING <span class="pi">//
//</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span>

<span class="string">"hebb0"</span>: <span class="string">"[SOUNDS]"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb1"</span>: <span class="string">"Anyway... how do we learn these fears in the first place?"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb2"</span>: <span class="string">"Well, to explain that, let me get rid of all this..."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb3"</span>: <span class="string">"and give you..."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb4"</span>: <span class="string">"this!"</span>,

<span class="string">"hebb5"</span>: <span class="string">"Hebbian Learning."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb6"</span>: <span class="string">"“Neurons that fire together, wire together.”"</span>,

<span class="string">"hebb7"</span>: <span class="string">"This is a rule of thumb that neuroscientists use to describe how"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb8"</span>: <span class="string">"neurons make new connections."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb9"</span>: <span class="string">"Basically, if you fire one neuron, then fire another neuron,"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb10"</span>: <span class="string">"the first neuron will connect TO the second neuron."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb11"</span>: <span class="string">"Try it out for yourself!"</span>,

<span class="string">"hebb12"</span>: <span class="string">"Too slow! You didn't click fast enough. Try again?"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb13"</span>: <span class="string">"Not close enough. Try a different pair of neurons."</span>,

<span class="string">"hebb14"</span>: <span class="string">"And that's how we learn!"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb15"</span>: <span class="string">"Of course, we don't learn that quickly in real life,"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb16"</span>: <span class="string">"I sped this simulation up, eh, but still."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb17"</span>: <span class="string">"Now play around, make a few more connections,"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb18"</span>: <span class="string">"maybe make a chain or something."</span>,

<span class="string">"hebb19"</span>: <span class="string">"This learning rule is why, if you were bitten by a dog as a kid,"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb20"</span>: <span class="string">"you might develop a fear of dogs!"</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb21"</span>: <span class="string">"Because your 'dog' neuron fired, then your 'pain' neuron fired."</span>,
<span class="string">"hebb22"</span>: <span class="string">"And thus, 'dog' connected to 'pain'."</span>,

<span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">///
//</span> ANTI-HEBBIAN LEARNING <span class="pi">//
//</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span>/

<span class="string">"anti0"</span>: <span class="string">"Anyway, if that's how we learn, here's how we un-learn."</span>,

<span class="string">"anti1"</span>: <span class="string">"Anti-Hebbian Learning."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti2"</span>: <span class="string">"“Neurons that fire out of sync, lose their link.”"</span>,

<span class="string">"anti3"</span>: <span class="string">"Another rule of thumb neuroscientists have!"</span>,

<span class="string">"anti4"</span>: <span class="string">"So - if you already have a connection from one neuron to another,"</span>,
<span class="string">"anti5"</span>: <span class="string">"and you fire the first neuron WITHOUT firing the second neuron,"</span>,
<span class="string">"anti6"</span>: <span class="string">"the connection weakens."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti7"</span>: <span class="string">"Again, try it out."</span>,

<span class="string">"anti8"</span>: <span class="string">"That neuron didn't have any connections."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti9"</span>: <span class="string">"You need to find one that's connected."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti10"</span>: <span class="string">"Ah, so that neuron only has connections going TO it, but not FROM it."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti11"</span>: <span class="string">"You need to find one that has connections FROM it."</span>,

<span class="string">"anti12"</span>: <span class="string">"Now wait for it..."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti13"</span>: <span class="string">"And look! The connection's weaker."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti14"</span>: <span class="string">"Do that again, and this time, the connection will be totally killed."</span>,

<span class="string">"anti15"</span>: <span class="string">"And this unlearning rule is why, if you have a fear of dogs,"</span>,
<span class="string">"anti16"</span>: <span class="string">"and you're exposed to friendly dogs over and over again,"</span>,
<span class="string">"anti17"</span>: <span class="string">"you might unlearn that fear."</span>,
<span class="string">"anti18"</span>: <span class="string">"'Dog' neuron gets fired, WITHOUT the 'pain' neuron getting fired,"</span>,
<span class="string">"anti19"</span>: <span class="string">"and therefore - the connection weakens."</span>,

<span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span>/
<span class="pi">// THERAPY //</span>
<span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span>/

<span class="string">"ther0"</span>: <span class="string">"So now that you know how we learn &amp; unlearn, let's revisit..."</span>,
<span class="string">"ther1"</span>: <span class="string">"...this."</span>,

<span class="string">"ther2"</span>: <span class="string">"I want you to re-train this brain."</span>,
<span class="string">"ther3"</span>: <span class="string">"Rewire, reconnect each of these three things,"</span>,
<span class="string">"ther4"</span>: <span class="string">"from feeling fear, to feeling safe."</span>,

<span class="string">"ther5"</span>: <span class="string">"See, rewiring yourself may cause anxiety in the short term..."</span>,
<span class="string">"ther6"</span>: <span class="string">"...but it is SO worth it in the long term."</span>,

<span class="string">"ther7"</span>: <span class="string">"One down, two more to go."</span>,
<span class="string">"ther8"</span>: <span class="string">"Two down, one more to go."</span>,
<span class="string">"ther9"</span>: <span class="string">"i. still. don't. like. holes."</span>,

<span class="string">"ther10"</span>: <span class="string">"And... you did it!"</span>,

<span class="string">"ther11"</span>: <span class="string">"What you just did is called 'exposure therapy'."</span>,
<span class="string">"ther12"</span>: <span class="string">"It's one of the most evidence-backed therapies out there"</span>,
<span class="string">"ther13"</span>: <span class="string">"for treating specific phobias, PTSD, and other anxiety disorders."</span>,

<span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">///
//</span> OUTRO <span class="pi">//
//</span><span class="pi">////</span><span class="pi">////</span>/

<span class="string">"outro0"</span>: <span class="string">"Again, in real life, rewiring yourself is not easy, it's not quick,"</span>,
<span class="string">"outro1"</span>: <span class="string">"but it can be done."</span>,
<span class="string">"outro2"</span>: <span class="string">"I promise you -- I'm proof --"</span>,
<span class="string">"outro3"</span>: <span class="string">"It can be done."</span>
</code></pre>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Introduce to a interesting website:<br><a href="http://ncase.me/neurons/?url_type=39&amp;object_type=webpage&amp;pos=1" target="_blank" r]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Neuro" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Neuro/"/>
    
      <category term="Inner_Man" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Inner-Man/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Say Hello]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2015/10/17/sayhello/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2015/10/17/sayhello/</id>
    <published>2015-10-17T15:19:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-20T16:25:10.510Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Say hello to world. 你好。</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Say hello to world. 你好。</p>
]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="uncategorized" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/uncategorized/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
